Register of the George Constantine Guins papers
Hoover Institution Archives
George Constantine Guins papers
1917-1971
XX314
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 9 microfilm reels (2.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, notes, reports, declarations, and printed matter relating to the Russian Revolution and Civil War in the Siberian Far East, activities of anti-Bolshevik forces in Siberia, Japanese intervention, and the history, culture and legal systems of Russia and the Soviet Union. Includes biographical data on members of the Guins family.
Guins, George Constantine, 1887-1971.
Location of Originals
In part, originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual or digital material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1887 April 27 (N.S.) Born, Novogeorgievsk, Russia (Modlin, Poland)
1909 Law degree, St. Petersburg University
1910 Entered government service, Resettlement Office of Ministry of Agriculture
1915 Law degree, St. Petersburg University
1916 Privat-Dozent, St. Petersburg University
1917 Chief Legal Counselor, Ministry of Provisions
1918-1920 Manager of Affairs, Siberian (later All-Russian) Provisional Government (also held positions of Assistant Minister of Foreign Affairs and Assistant Minister of Education, Chairman of State Economic Council)
1921 Author, Sibir', soiuzniki i Kolchak
1921-1926 Service on administration of Chinese Eastern Railway as Head of Chancellery and later Chief Controller
1927 Author, Eticheskie problemy sovremennogo Kitaia
1928 Author, Obosnovanie politiki prava v trudakh Professora L.I. Petrazhitskogo
1929 Law degree, Paris
1931-1932 Author, Novye idei v prave i osnovnye problemy sovremennosti
1933 Author, Uchenie o prave i politicheskaia ekonomiia
1936 Author, Ocherki sotsial'noi psikhologii
1940 Author, Predprinimatel'
1941 Author, Quo Vadis Europa?
1941 Immigrated to the United States
1946-1953 Lecturer, University of California, Berkeley
1954-1964 Consultant, Voice of America, United States Information Agency
1971 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection consists mainly of the speeches, writings and lectures of George C. Guins for his émigré period.
The collection contains important biographical material, including his third person autobiography and oral history interviews. Also of particular significance are his unpublished book manuscripts on the development of Russian history and culture, as well as on his academic specialty - legal theory.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials and copyright to them (with some exceptions) are the property of the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920.; Siberia (Russia)--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Russia--History.; Russia--Civilization.; Law--Soviet Union.; Russians--United States.; Guins family
- Not yet described (Boxes 1-4)
- Photographs, undated (Envelope A)
  Scope and Contents note
  37 photographs / 1 envelope. 2 prints of Admiral Aleksandr K. Kolchak; 1 print of General Mikhail K. Dietrichs; 1 print of General Jan Syrovy; 1 print of P. V. Vologodskago; 1 print of Ivan I. Serebrennikov; 1 print of Lev M. Mikhailov; 1 print of Zefirov; 1 print of Steponenkol 1 print of Gudkov; 1 print of Gratsianov; 1 print of Shchmelovsky; 1 print of Sapoznikov; 1 print of Potushchapsky; 2 unidentified prints of people; 22 prints of scenes in Siberia.
- Microfilm reel (Microfilm cabinet)
  Razvitie Bol'shevizma na Dal'nem Vostoke: Ocherk po materialam inspektsii Kraevoi militisii pri Verkhovnom upolnomochennom Rossiiskogo Pravitel'stva na Dal'nem Vostoke. Edited by Colonel von Arnold. Vladivostok, May 1919.
- Biographical File, 1917-1971
  Personal and financial papers, identity documents, oral history interviews, autobiographical notes and correspondence, bibliography of works, farewell addresses, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also: Speeches and Writings and Oversize File.
  - Addresses honoring Guins [See also: Oversize File]
    - On the occasion of leaving the service of the Chinese Eastern Railroad (in Chinese), 1926 (Reel 1)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 1
    - On the occasion of the tenth anniversary of Guins's teaching political economy at the First Harbin Public Commercial School, 1941 (Reel 1)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 2
  - Autobiographical note and brief resume (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 3
  - Bibliography of works published (to 1949) (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 4
  - Correspondence relating biographical information for oral history project, undated (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 5
    Includes letters to director of UC Berkeley Regional Oral History Office Willa Baum and interviewer Boris Raymond.
  - Oral history projects conducted by the Regional Oral History Office of the University of California, Berkeley
    - George C. Guins: Impressions of the Russian Imperial Government (Berkeley, CA: University of California Regional Oral History Office), 1971 (Reel 1)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 6
    - George C. Guins, Professor and Government Official: Russia, China and California. An Interview Conducted by Boris Raymond (Berkeley, CA: University of California Regional Oral History Office), 1966 (Reel 1)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 7
  - Miscellaneous documents, including travel certificates, identity papers, power of attorney forms and a contract form (typescript, apparently drawn up by Guins), service and financial records (in Russian and Chinese, with attached photographs), 1917-1941 (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 8
- Correspondence, 1950-1964
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General and unidentified, undated-1964 (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 9
  - Beliaev, Nikolai Pavlovich, 1950 (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 10
  - Gsowska, Helena, 1964 (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 11
  - Paramonov, Sergei Iakovlevich, 1955 (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 12
  - Taylor, Pauline, 1964 (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 1: 13
- Speeches and Writings, 1918-1964
  Speeches, drafts of articles and books, offprints, reviews and related correspondence, arranged chronologically and by title thereunder.
  - General
    - Fragments
      - Biography of Admiral Kolchak, typescript, undated (Reel 1)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 1
      - Works on the Russian Civil War and Allied intervention, typescript (in Russian and English), undated (Reel 1)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 2
      - Work(s) on the Slav question at the close of World War II, typescript, undated (Reel 1)
        Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 3
    - Notes, holograph, undated (Reel 1)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 4
    - Research materials on Soviet law, holograph and typescript, circa 1954-1955 (Reel 1)
      Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 5
  - "Aggression - A Challenge to the U.N.," typescript, undated (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 6
  - "Anglichanin o russkikh i o sovetskoi zhizni," typescript, undated (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 7
  - "Beloe dvizhenie," background material, notes, related fragments and typescript (incomplete), including early draft(s), undated (Reel 1)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 8
  - "Beloe dvizhenie i ego razvitie," typescript (incomplete), undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 9
    Includes early draft(s).
  - "Chego strana zhdet ot Aika Eisenhauera?," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 10
  - "Chekhoslovakiia i Rossiia," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 11
  - "Chelovek v Sovetskom gosudarstve," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 12
  - "Chto proiskhodit v mire?," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 13
  - "Comrades But Not Brothers!," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 14
  - "D. P." [speech], notes, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 15
  - "Dva Verkhovnykh suda," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 16
  - "Dvortsovyi perevorot v Moskve," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 17
  - "Fashizm," holograph, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 18
    Includes early draft entitled "O fashizme."
  - "The Fateful Events of the W. W. II," notes and typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 19
  - "The Influence of Social Culture on Human Behavior," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 20
  - "The International Peace Army (IPA)," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 21
  - "Iron Curtain Laws and Convictions by False Confessions," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 22
  - "Is Comintern Suspended or Dead?," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 23
  - "Kakovo zhe budushchee Rossii," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 24
  - "Kul'tura natsionalnykh menshinstv v S.S.S.R.," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 25
  - "Legal Policy (Principles of Legislation and Administration)" [See: "Politika prava (osnovy zakonodatel'stva i upravleniia)," undated] (Reel 3)
  - "Lozungi prezidenta Eizenkhauera," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 26
  - "Makhnovtsy i zelenye," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 27
  - "Na poroge novogo goda," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 28
  - "Nad svezhei mogiloi E.P. Grot," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 29
  - "Nakanune Zhenevskoi konferentsii," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 30
  - "Napoleon XX-go veka," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 31
  - "The National Question and Revolution," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 32
  - "Natsional'naia problema i budushchee Rossii," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 33
  - "Natsional'naia problema v Rossii," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 34
  - "Neodolimaia sila," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 35
  - "Ob iazyke i pol'zovan'i im," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 36
  - "Obedinennye natsii," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 37
  - "Obedinennye natsii i prezident de Goll'," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 2: 38
  - "Obshchaia teoriia prava," holograph and typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 3: 1-2
    Includes background material, notes, and drafts of a proposed book. Materials have been left in original order, which may or may not reflect author's order, with the exception of placement of table of contents at beginning. Some of the content is in the form of a revised draft of material previously published. Includes early titles and/or drafts of sections entitled "Psikhologicheskaia teoriia prava," "Sotsial'naia psikhologiia i pravo," and "Sotsiologicheskie i psikhologicheskie predposylki novykh idei v prave," 1933; notes for speech entitled "Sotsial'naia psikhologiia i osnovy prava," 1936 September 8, before the Kharbinskii Iuridicheskii Fakul'tet, Harbin, China; and news clipping summarizing speech ( Gun-Bao, 9 September 1936).
  - "Odin iz retseptov," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 3: 3
  - "Perevoploshchenie Peterburga," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 3: 4
  - "Peterburgskie biurokraty predrevoliutsionnogo vremeni," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 3: 5
  - "Pochemu kul't Pushkina," holograph, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 3: 6
  - "Poeziia Lermontova i sovremennost'," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 3: 7
  - "Politicheskie prognozy," typescript, undated (Reel 2)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 3: 8
  - "Politika prava (osnovy zakonodatel'stva i upravleniia)," typescript, undated (Reel 3)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 3: 9-11
    Consists of incomplete Russian original, with drafts of material re-used from published works, as well as drafts of English translations entitled "Legal Policy (Principles of Legislation and Administration)," and "Law Making as a Science."
  - "Prisoedinenie Srednei Azii," typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 1
  - "Programma obnovleniia," typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 2
  - "Psikhologicheskaia teoriia prava" [See "Obshchaia teoriia prava," undated] (Reel 2)
  - Review of Harry Braverman, The Future of Russia, typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 3
  - Review of Ivo Lapenna, State and Law: Soviet and Yugoslav Theory, typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 4
  - Review of M. G. Levin and L. P. Potapov, editors, The Peoples of Siberia, typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 5
  - Review of William Petersen, ed., The Realities of World Communism, typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 6
  - "Revolution Is Still a Hope," typescript (incomplete), undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 7
  - "Russia Will Overcome Japan," typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 8
  - "The Russians Among Us," typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 9
  - "Russia's and Soviet Culture (A Philosophy of Russian History)," typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 10
    Incomplete work consisting of background notes, partial table of contents, preface (in Russian and two English versions), early drafts of chapters V ("Mongol'skaia imperiia," with fragment in English) and VII ("The New Generation" - chapter XXII in the final draft), and a section entitled "Part III: Soviet Culture" (chapter XII through conclusion).
  - "Russkaia revoliutsiia v plane mirovoi istorii," typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 11
  - "Samoe dorogoe zdanie v mire," typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 12
  - "Siberia and Its Peoples," typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 13
  - "Soiuzniki i Rossiia v gody revoliutsii," notes, early drafts, fragments and typescript (incomplete), undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 14
  - "Sotsialisticheskaia zakonnost'," typescript and abridged English translation ("Socialist Legality"), undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 15
  - "Sotsial'naia psikhologiia i pravo" [See: "Obshchaia teoriia prava," undated] (Reel 2)
  - "Stolitsa S.Sh.A.," typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 16
  - "Trevozhnye simptomy," typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 17
  - "Ukraina posle revoliutsii," research notes and typescript, undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 18
  - Untitled draft of book(s) on development of USSR in the post-World War II period (industry, society, law, ideology, constitutional and political issues), holograph and typescript (in Russian and English), undated (Reel 4)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 4: 19-20
    May include chapters and fragments related to other works.
  - Untitled draft of book(s) on Russian foreign relations (historical development and the post-World War II period), typescript, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 1
  - Untitled work on Solidarism, typescript, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 2
  - "V Kaliforniiskom universitete," typescript, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 3
  - "Verkhovnyi sud i Kongress," typescript, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 4
  - "Verkhovnyi sud. Pamiati F. Frankfurtera," typescript, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 5
  - "Vosstanovlenie obshchei istorii: Malorossiia posle vossoedineniia," typescript, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 6
  - "Vremennoe Pravitel'stvo i Bol'shevizm: Vospominaniia i razmyshleniia," typescript, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 7
  - "The World in the Process of Reconstruction," typescript, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 8
  - "Za i protiv," typescript, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 9
  - "Zagadochnye ieroglify," typescript, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 10
  - "Znachenie literatury," holograph, undated (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 11
  - Eticheskie problemy sovremennogo Kitaia, Harbin, printed copy, 1927 (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 12
  - Obosnovanie politiki prava v trudakh Professora L. I. Petrazhitskogo, Harbin, printed copy, 1928 (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 13
  - L. I. Petrazhitskii: Kharakteristika nauchnogo tvorchestva, 1867-1931 g. g., Harbin, printed copy (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 14
  - "Russkaia obshchestvennaia kultura i reformy Imper. Al. II," holograph, [1931] (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 15
  - Novye idei v prave i osnovnye problemy sovremennosti. Vypusk 1, Harbin, printed copy, 1931 (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 16
  - Novye idei v prave i osnovnye problemy sovremennosti. Vypusk 2, Harbin, printed copy, 1932 (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 17
  - Uchenie o prave i politicheskaia ekonomiia, Harbin, printed copy, 1933 (Reel 5)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 5: 18
  - "Sotsiologicheskie i psikhologicheskie predposylki novykh idei v prave" [See: "Obshchaia teoriia prava," undated], 1933 (Reel 2)
  - "Starye i novye liudi," speech, Kharbinskoe Kommercheskoe Sobranie, Harbin, China, holograph and printed broadside advertising speech, 1933 November 15 (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 1
  - "Sotsial'naia psikhologiia i osnovy prava" [See: "Obshchaia teoriia prava," undated], 1936 September 8 (Reel 2)
  - The Entrepreneur, Harbin, typescript, 1940 (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 2
  - "Vospominaniia o S.P.B. Universitete," holograph, [1941] (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 3
  - "Epokha velikikh reform," holograph, 1941 November 10-20 (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 4
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings consisting of Guins' articles, circa 1942-1947 (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 5
    Includes biographical note supplied to Museum of Russian Culture, undated.
  - "Basic Principles of U.N.R.R.A.'s Policy," Southwestern Social Science Quarterly, printed copy, 1945 September (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 6
  - "Russia and the United States in the World Economy," American Journal of Economics and Sociology, printed copy, 1946 January (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 7
  - "Two Worlds in One: Revolution Against Reform," American Journal of Economics and Sociology, printed copy, 1946 July (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 8
    Includes a typescript entitled "Two Worlds in 'One World'."
  - "Rokovye liudi," Russkaia zhizn', printed copy, 1946 September 14 (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 9
  - "Russia's Prize in Manchuria," Russian Review, Autumn. printed copy, 1946 (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 10
    Includes typescript "Russkii priz v Man'chzhurii," undated.
  - "Korean Plans of Russian Imperialism," American Journal of Economics and Sociology, printed copy, 1946 October (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 11
    Includes typed draft "Russia and Korea," undated.
  - "Soviet Culture: Old Trends and New," Russian Review, printed copy, 1947 Autumn (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 12
  - "The Degeneration of 'Pan-Slavism'," American Journal of Economics and Sociology, 1948 October (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 13
    Includes "The Politics of 'Pan-Slavism'," American Journal of Economics and Sociology, 1949 January and "The Prospects of 'Pan-Slavism'," American Journal of Economics and Sociology, 1950 July, printed copies. Also includes two typed drafts (one incomplete) of the entire work in English under the title "The Slav Question" and one typed draft in Russian, "Slavianskii vopros" (also entitled "Chapter XIV").
  - "A. S. Pushkin (1799-1849)," typescript, [1949] (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 14
  - "East and West in Soviet Ideology," Russian Review, printed copy, 1949 October (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 15
  - "A. N. Ostrovskii i sovremennost'," typescript, [1950] (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 16
  - "Soviet Law -- Terra Incognita," Russian Review, printed copy, 1950 January (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 17
  - "Soviet Centralism," American Journal of Economics and Sociology, printed copy, 1950 April (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 18
  - "Penalties and Rewards in Soviet Law," Washington Law Review, printed copy, 1950 May (Reel 6)
    Museum of Russian Culture Box/Folder 6: 19
  - "Law Does Not Wither Away in the Soviet Union," Russian Review, printed copy, 1950 July (Reel 6)